Their escape was just the beginning.
The Way Back is a drama, adventure, history film directed by Peter Weir.
A small band of multicultural convicts stages a daring escape from a WWII-era Siberian gulag, and embarks on
a treacherous journey across five countries in a desperate race for freedom and survival.
Mr. Smith, played by Ed Harris.
Janusz Wieszczek, played by Jim Sturgess.
Irena Zielińska, played by Saoirse Ronan.
Valka, played by Colin Farrell.
Andrei Khabarov, played by Mark Strong.
Andrejs Voss, played by Gustaf Skarsgård.
The Way Back is a 2010 American survival film directed by Peter
Weir, from a screenplay by Weir and Keith Clarke.
The film is inspired by The Long Walk (1956), the memoir by former Polish prisoner of war Sławomir Rawicz, who
claimed to have escaped from a Soviet Gulag and walked 4,000 miles (6,400 km) to freedom in World War II.
The film stars Jim Sturgess, Colin Farrell, Ed Harris, and Saoirse Ronan, with Alexandru
Potocean, Sebastian Urzendowsky, Gustaf Skarsgård, Dragoș Bucur and Mark Strong.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and was
nominated for an Oscar for Best Makeup, but lost to The Wolfman.
The nomination was received by Gregory Funk, Edouard F.
Henriques and Yolanda Toussieng.
The film explores themes of escape, world war ii,
soviet union, anti-communism, india.
The tone is emotional.